Inventory of the Woolfolk Family Papers 1775-1893
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Woolfolk Family Papers, 1775-1893
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 W88
Lot 1: 3,980 items; Lot 2: 6,000 items.
Correspondence and business records of members of the Woolfolk family of Caroline County, Virginia, dating 1775-1893. The Woollfolk family was engaged in two firms and a stage line.
Woolfolk family;; Maury family;; Woolfolk, John George, 1750-1819;; Woolfolk, Jourdan, b. 1796;; Woolfolk, Pichegru;; Woolfolk, John William;; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829;; Ryland, Robert, 1805-1899;; Waller, Benjamin.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 3,980 items, 5 November 1937. Gift: 6,000 items, 27 June 1939.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Woolfolk family originally emigrated from Wales. John George Woolfolk (1750-1819) ran a stage line and had a contract to carry the mail. His sons Pichegru Woolfolk and Jourdan Woolfolk continued the stage line. Jourdan had a son, John William Woolfolk, among other children.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of the Woolfolk family of Caroline County, Virginia including correspondence and accounts of John George Woolfolk, Jourdan Woolfolk, Pichegru Woolfolk and John William Woolfolk. The collection includes correspondence, accounts and vouchers for the stage line run by the Woolfolk family (Allen & Woolfolk; Jourdan Woolfolk & Company; and Woolfolk & Hoomes). Includes records of routes, rates, supplies, arrangements for layover of passengers and mail contracts of the Potomac Steamboat and Stage Company as well as papers concerning stock purchases in the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad. Also includes bound account books for the stage lines. Note: Includes letters written by James Lyons, Timothy Pickering, Robert Ryland and Benjamin Waller; letters of and accounts concerning members of the Maury family; and lists, 1829 and 1837, of vaccinated slaves. Lot 2 consists of about 6000 pieces of papers of the Woolfolk Family of Caroline County, Virgini, dated 1793-1876. There are financial records relating to the stage line and mailservice, records relating to agricultural business, correspondence, insurance records, military records, records relating to the erection of Antioch Baptist Church, and copies of newspapers.
Arrangement
Organization
Organized into 14 series. Lot 1 comprises series 1-7. Lot 2 comprises series 8-14. There is a certain overlap between some of the series of lot 1 and 2. Lot 2 is has not been processed beyond the Series arrangement. Series 1: Correspondence relating to the stage line; Series 2: Accounts and vouchers of the stage line; Series 3: Other papers relating to the stage line and the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad; Series 4: Correspondence of the Woolfolk family; Series 5: Papers of various persons, A-Z; Series 6: Other Papers; Series 7: Bound volumes; Series 8: Papers relating to the stage and mail service operated by members of the Woolfolk Family; Series 9: Papers relating to members of the Woolfolk Family, A-Z; Series 10: Papers relating to the estate of John Hoomes; Series 11: Subscription lists, invoices and receipts relative to the erection of Antioch Christian Church, Bowling Green, Virginia; Series 12: Records of the Caroline troop of cavalry, 1816-1820; Series 13: Newspapers; Series 14: Miscellaneous.
Arrangement
Lot 1: The series are arranged chronologically, with the exception of series 5, which is arranged alphabetically by last name and chronologically within. Lot 2: Series 9 is arranged alphabetically by last name; the other series of Lot 2 have not been further arranged at this point.
Index Terms
Family name:
Maury family.; Woolfolk family.
Corporate name:
Potomac Steamboat and Stage Company.; Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railraod Compnay..
Subjects:
Postal service- -United States--History.; Transportation--Virginia.; Coaching--United States.; Slavery--Virginia--19th century.
Geographical name:
Caroline County (Va.)--History -- 18th century.; Caroline County (Va.)--History -- 19th century.
Persons:
Woolfolk, John George, 1750-1819.; Woolfolk, Jourdan, b. 1796.; Woolfolk, Pichegru.; Woolfolk, John William.; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829.; Ryland, Robert, 1805-1899.; Waller, Benjamin.
Contents List
  Series 1: Correspondence relating to the stage line
- Correspondence relating to the stage line, 1795-1844, 1938. (Box-folder 1:1-1:2)
  - Old Mulberry Place, 2 January 1938. (Box-folder 1:1)
    An article by Vera Palmer in the Richmond Times Dispatch, January 2, 1938, concerning the Woolfolk family, the stage line, and Mulberry Place, the Woolfolk plantation in Caroline County, Virginia.
  - Correspondence relating to the stage line operated by members of the Woolfolk family, 1795-1844., 177 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
    This file contains also letters relating to the carrying mails and to connections with the Fredericksburg and Potomac Steamship Company, and the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad.
  Series 2: Accounts and vouchers of the stage line
- Accounts and vouchers of the stage line, 1788-1845. (Box-folder 1:3-2:6)
  chronological
  - Accounts of the stage line operated by members of the Woolfolk family, 1788-1845., 754 items. (Box-folder 1:3-2:6)
    This file contains also accounts of the Potomac Steamboat and Stage Company and accounts for the carrying of mail. All the accounts after 1840 pertain to the carrying of mail. See also Bound Volumes.
  Series 3: Papers relating to the stage line and the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad
- Papers relating to the stage line and the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad, 1796-1851. (Box-folder 3:7)
  Arranged into two groups: papers realting to the stage line are followed by papers relating to the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad, within each group chronological.
  - Robert Armistead to William Townes and Alexander McRae, 1796., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:7)
    Trust deed to secure payment to John G. Woolfolk for the purchase of his interest in the stage line from Richmond to Norfolk and in the carrying of mail by that line, and from Osborns to Bermuda hundred.
  - Papers relating to the purchase of horses probably used for the stage line, 1811-1831., 10 items. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Schedule of fares from Richmond to Fredericksburg, ca. 1820., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Agreement of Edwin Porter & Co., and Jourdan Woolfolk with N. C. Lipscomb concerning the boarding of stage drivers and passengers, 1823., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Contract of Jourdan Woolfolk with the United States for carrying mail from Bowling Green, Virginia, by Turner's Store, to White Chimneys, and back, twice a week, 1838., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Contract of Jourdan Woolfolk with the United States for carrying the mail from Bowling Green, Virginia, by Turner's Store and White Chimneys, to Mahgohic, and back, twice a week, 1843., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - List of subscribers to the Richmond and Potomac railroad survey whose subscriptions were returned by Jourdan Woolfolk, 1834., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Papers relating to cash transactions of Jourdan Woolfolk with the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad, 1835-1837., 14 items. (Box-folder 3:7)
    Includes several receipts for cash paid in purchase of stock.
  - Vouchers relating to payments for and dividends on stock in the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad purchased by Pichegru and John Woolfolk, 1835-1876., 8 items. (Box-folder 3:7)
  Series 4: Correspondence of the Woolfolk family
- Correspondence of the Woolfolk family, 1793-1836. (Box-folder 3:8-9)
  chronologically
  - R. Woolfolk, at Redstone, to his brother, John G. Woolfolk, 18 October 1793. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - John Hoomes, Jr., at London, [England], to John G. Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, [Caroline County], Virginia, 22 July 1800. (Box-folder 3:8)
    Enclosure: Invoice for goods purchased of E. Andrews by John Hoomes for John G. Woolfolk.
  - Brown, Younger & Co., at London, to John Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Virginia, 21 February 1806., Printed circular letter. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Robert Patton, at Philadelphia, to John G. Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Virginia 14 July 1807. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - John Taylor, at Hazelwood, [Caroline County, Virginia], to John G. Woolfolk, at Shepherd's Hill, Caroline [County] 18 July 1807. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Timothy Pickering, at Wenham, near Salem, Mass., to John G. Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Virginia, 8 August 1808. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Benjamin Wailer, at Williamsburg, to John Woolfolk, near Bowling Green, Caroline County, 13 August 1810 and 24 August 1810. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Henry P. Brodnax, at Frankfort, [Kentucky], to [John Woolfolk], 2 January 1811. (Box-folder 3:8)
    Enclosure: Certificate of redemption by Henry P. Brodnax for John Woolfolk of four tracts of land in Lincoln, Shelby, and Hardin Counties, Kentucky, which had been sold for taxes.
  - T. B. Brodnax to [?], 8 December 1812. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Richard Woolfolk, at Richmond, to [?], 12 April 1814. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - George D. Baylor, at New Market, [Shenandoah County], to John G. Woolfolk, at Shepherds Hill, Caroline County, 22 November 1814. (Box-folder 3:8)
    Note: A receipt for money allowed Thomas Swann by the overseers of the poor appears on the same sheet.
  - Benjamin Wailer, at Williamsburg, to [?], 22 February 1816. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Elizabeth P. Woolfolk to Richard Wortham, at Richmond, 25 November 1823. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - W. Alien to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 18 January 1827. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - William G. Maury to Jourdan Woolfolk, 5 April 1828 and 9 July 1828. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - James Lyons, at Richmond, to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 9 January 1831. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - James Lyons, at Richmond, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at White Chimneys, Caroline County, Virginia, 9 November 1833. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - M. Sizer to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, 12 March 1836. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - N. Dickerson, Navy Department, to Midshipman William Lewis Maury, U.S. Navy, Bowling Green, Virginia, 21 May 1836. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - William W. Dickerson, at Ruther Glen, [Caroline County], to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 23 September 1836. (Box-folder 3:8)
    Enclosure: An account of James Covington with William W. Dickinson.
  - Charles Morris to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 10 October 1836 and 17 December 1836. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Benjamin Anderson to Jourdan Woolfolk, 31 December 1836. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - R. Gwathmey to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Mulberry Place, Caroline [County, Virginia], 26 March 1837. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - William W. Taylor, at Taylorsville, to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 10 June 1837. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Robert Hood, at Port Royal, [Caroline County], to General Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 16 June 1838. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - H. P. Taylor, at Rose Cottage, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Greenk, 26 October 1838. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - John W. Maury, at Washington, [D.C.], to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 16 January 1839. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Hugh M. Patten, cashier, Farmers Branch Bank, at Fredericksburg, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, 21 January 1839. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - R. Ryland, at the [Virginia Baptist] Seminary [i.e. Richmond College], to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Virginia, 10 December 1840. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Williamson Talley, at The Meadows, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, 14 February 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
    Date is that of postmark, New Amsterdam, Hanover County, Virginia.
  - P. Bradley, at Washington, [D.C.], to William Allen, at Bowling Green, Virginia, 6 April 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
    This letter contains information about contracts for carrying mail.
  - H. H. Martin to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, 8 May 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - James Hunter to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 20 May 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Charles Morris to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 20 May 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Hardin [?], at Taylorsville, to Jourdan Woolfolk, near Milford Depot, Caroline [County], 23 December 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - J. DuVal, King & Queen [County], to Jourdan Woolfolk, Caroline [County], 27 December 1841. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - S. C. Grammer, president, Franklin Insurance Company, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 1 March 1842., Postmarked Washington, D. C. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Joseph M. Sheppard, Hanover County, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, 4 March 1842. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - John W. Maury, at Washington, [D. C.], to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 12 March 1842. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Anne Roberts, at Manchester, [Chesterfield County], to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 1 December 1842. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Anderson Barret, at Richmond, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County], 31 December 1842. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Gay Williamson], at Norfolk, to her cousin, John Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 19 June 1843 and 16 February 1844. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - , Gabe [?], at Norfolk, to John Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia,11 March 1844. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Gay Williamson, at Norfolk, to John Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 15 January 1845. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Joseph M. Sheppard, at Richmond, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 15 November 1848. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Lewis Hill, at Richmond, to John Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 7 September 1850. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Charles Herndon, at Fredericksburg, to John Woolfolk, 6 May 1851. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - W. K. Pendleton, at Bethany College, Brooke County, Virginia, to Edmond T. Morris, at Junction Post Office, Hanover County, Virginia, 22 May 1851. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - R. L. Coleman, at Glen Cottage, to [?] Woolfolk, 31 May 1861. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - R. Edmond, at Richmond, to F. Woolfolk, 30 December 1866. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Robert Y. Henley, at Edgemont, King & Queen County, Virginia, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, 5 June 1867. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - S. F. Winston, at Gonzales, Texas, to John William Woolfolk, 30 September 1876. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - James Hunter, at Fredericksburg, to Jourdan Woolfolk, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 3:9)
  Series 5: Papers of various persons, A-Z
- Papers of various persons, A-Z, 1775-1860. (Box-folder 4:10-10:28)
  Arranged alphabetically, within each name chronologically.
  - Albright (George L.) to John and Philip Chapman, 1831., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Note.
  - Allen (Wilson), 1830., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Agreement of Pleasant Terrell and Lewis Webb Co., creditors of Wilson Allen.
  - Jourdan Woolfolk, guardian of Apperson (Richard), 1830-1838. (Box-folder 4:10)
    See also Bound Volumes.
  - Bailey (Chester), 1811., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Invoice.
  - Burke (John M.) estate, 1822-1848. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Invoices, receipts, notes, memoranda. Note: Jourdan Woolfolk was administrator. See also Bound Volumes.
  - Jourdan Woolfolk, guardian of Burke (Maria L.), 1848-1850. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Invoices.
  - Jourdan Woolfolk, guardian of Burke (Mary Ellen) and Jourdan Burke, 1846-1860., 31 pieces. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Chapman (John) and Philip Chapman vs. Samuel Wade, 1824., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Suit in Caroline County.
  - Coleman (Mary), 1818., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Draft in favor of A. Samuel.
  - Covington (William), 1854-1856., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Crawford [?], 1814., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Davis (William), 1809-1810., 8 pieces. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Hardaman (Patsey) estate, 1845. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Hill (Andrew), 1830-1839. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Invoives.
  - John G. Woolfolk, guardian of Hoomes (Miss), 1806., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Hoomes (John) estate, 1784-1821., 22 items. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Papers relating to the estate of John Hoomes, including accounts and invoices of John Hoomes and Company. This group contains a statement of tobacco shipped in 1799, giving the names of planters.
  - Hoomes (John W.) vs. John Hoomes, executor of John Hoomes et als., 1824., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Suit in Fredericksburg, Virginia.
  - Hoomes (Richard) and wife to Reuban Tankersley, 1823., 1 item, copy. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Deed to a tract of land in Caroline County called Millford.
  - Jacobs (Benjamin), 1811., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Receipt.
  - Jones (Eleanor), 1826., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Jones (Thomas) estate, 1775-1809., 40 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Papers relating to the estate of Thomas Jones.
  - Long (John) estate, 1806-1837., 28 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Papers relating to a trusteeship for the benefits of Catharine Long, wife of John Long.
  - Jourdan Woolfolk, trustee for Maury (Ann H.) and children, 1838-1843., 7 pieces. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Legal papers and invoices. See also Bound Volumes.
  - Maury (William G.) and wife to James Brown, Jr., and William Finney, trustees for John Adams and Samuel G. Adams, 1817., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Deed of trust covering certain lots of land in or near the city of Richmond.
  - Maury (William G.), 1822-1832., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Invoice and drafts. See also Bound Volumes.
  - Maury (William L.), 1935-1837., 7 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Invoice and receipts.
  - Prager (Frederick) to John M. Gray, 1814., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Reynolds (James C.), 1830., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Tankersley (Reuben) estate, 1846., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Bond given by Bill Jones, Pichegru Woolfolk and others to secure payment of rent for a tract of land in Caroline County, called Milford, belonging to the estate of Reuben Tankersley.
  - Walden (George), Clerks' fees and taxes., 4 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Clerks' fees and taxes.
  - Winston (Edmund), 1875., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Agreement for lease of a house to Richard Cross.
  - Winston (S.F. and M.E.) 1874. (Box-folder 4:11)
    Draft of an agreement drawn up by John W. Woolfolk, agent of S. F. and M. E. Winston, for the lease of Shepherds Hill, Caroline County. The name of the lessee is not given.
  - Woolfolk [?], 1826-1842., 6 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
    Invoice and memoranda.
  - Woolfolk (Angelina F.) to R. W. McGruder, 1848., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
    Bill of sale for a dress.
  - Woolfolk (Anna), 1840-1841., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Woolfolk (Elizabeth P.), 1827., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
    Deed of gift for a horse given by Elizabeth P. Woolfolk to John Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk, Elizabeth P., estate, 1820-1840., 117 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
    Accounts and invoices.
  - Woolfolk (Frances), 1821., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
    Agreement of Frances Woolfolk with John W. Coleman, Pichegru Woolfolk and Sublett McGruder concerning the support and use of negroes.
  - Woolfolk, Frances, estate, 1794-1805., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
    Accounts.
  - Woolfolk (John) estate, 1851., 1 item, copy. (Box-folder 5:13)
    Copy of the court order for the appraisal of the John Woolfolk estate.
  - Woolfolk (John) estate, 1819-1872., 216 items. (Box-folder 5:13-14)
    Accounts and invoices of the John Woolfolk estate including the trusteeship of Mary Elizabeth Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk (John) estate., 1866., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Agreement of Jourdan Woolfolk and John W. Woolfolk, trustees of Mary Elizabeth Woolfolk, with Emily G. Carrett and James Garrett, for the rental of Sheperds Hill, Caroline County.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Murry i.e. Maury (William G.) to Richard C. Wortham, trustee for John G. Woolfolk, 1819., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Trust deed covering certain lots of land in or near the city of Richmond, also certain slaves and personal property.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Mutual Assurance Society against fire on buildings in the State of Virginia vs. John G. Woolfolk, 1810., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Mutual Assurance Society against fire on buildings of the State of Virginia vs. Elizabeth Woolfolk, tenant, and John G. Woolfolk, reversioner, 1823., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Woolfolk (John George), 1787-1810., 6 items. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Bills of sale for slaves purchased by John G. Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk (John George), 1804-1816., 18 pieces. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Papers relating to the controversy over a portion of the Chase tract of land in Caroline County, sold by Carter Beverley to John G. Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Jourdan Woolfolk, John M. Burke and Hawes Coleman, administrators of Woolfolk (John C.) vs. Benjamin Haley, 1818., 2 items. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Suit in Richmond.
  - Woolfolk (John George, estate, 1820., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Agreement between Jourdan Woolfolk, Hawes Coleman and John M. Burke, administrators.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Hawes Coleman and John M. Burke, administrators of Woolfolk (John G.) vs. Jourdan Woolfolk, trustee under the will of John G. Woolfolk, for Nancy H. Maury et als., 1821., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Suit in Fredericksburg.
  - Woolfolk (John George), Hawes Coleman, Jourdan Woolfolk and John M. Burke, administrators of Woolfolk (John C.) to Elizabeth Woolfolk, 1826., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Bill of sale for negroes.
  - Woolfolk (John George), 1847., 4 items. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Bonds given by the heirs of Sophia F. Burke to John Woolfolk to protect him against loss in the settlement of the estate of John C. Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Agreement of Jourdan Woolfolk, surviving administrator, with the heirs of John C. Woolfolk, 1847., Unsigned copy with incomplete date 1847. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Murry i.e. Maury (William C.) to Richard C. Wortham, trustee for John C. Woolfolk, 1819., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Mutual Assurance Society against fire on buildings in the State of Virginia vs. John C. Woolfolk, 1810., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Mutual Assurance Society against fire on buildings of the State of Virginia vs. Elizabeth Woolfolk, tenant, and John C. Woolfolk, reversioner, 1823., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George), 1787-1810., 6 items. (Box-folder 6:16)
    Bills of sale for slaves purchased by John C. Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk (John George), 1804-1816., 18 items. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Jourdan Woolfolk, John N. Burke and Hawes Coleman, administrators of Woolfolk (John G.) vs. Benjamin Haley, 1818., 2 items. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Woolfolk (John C.) estate, 1820., 1 piece. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Hawes Coleman and John M. Burke, administrators of Woolfolk (John C.) vs. Jourdan Woolfolk, trustee under the will of John G. Woolfolk, for Nancy H. Maury et als., 1821., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Woolfolk (John George), 1794-1850., 449 items. (Box-folder 6:16-17)
    Invoices, receipts and drafts. Including accounts of the estate and correspondence concerning accounts.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Letters from Thomas Goodwin, Farmer's Bank, Fredericksburg, concerning notes of John G. Woolfolk in the bank, 1819-1822., 33 items. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Some of the letters are addressed to Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Woolfolk (John George): Invoices, bonds and drafts of John G. Woolfolk and John Hoomes, 1800-1810. (Box-folder 6:18)